Ignacio García-Carrillo

Pennington, New Jersey, United States

ignaciogcarrillo@outlook.com

+16096909430

linkedin.com/in/ignaciogarciacarrillo

Summary

Over 20 years of progressive experience spanning full range of Telecom, IT and Cloud business solutions, including services, software and hardware, in diverse positions spanning from general management, to sales, marketing, business development, product management, architecture, engineering, training, delivery or research.

Innovation expert, results focused, hands on technical sales leader, excels at business development, through best in class Telecom, IT and Cloud business and solution knowledge, C-level customer orientation, business value assessment, organization, methodology and attention to detail.

Extensive sales & project experience in Europe, USA, Canada and Latin America. Fluent Spanish & English. Medium level Portuguese.

- Led new business creation and new account penetration in 22 countries in America and Europe with a team of more than 150 account managers and technical experts
- Corporate executive relocation to the USA and now back to Belgium by Hewlett-Packard. Part of HP's Talent program. Mentor and experienced manager of global teams
- Led or was key part in the creation of five new HPE Telecom products that led to revenues in excess of \$200M and serve hundreds of millions of subscribers worldwide
- Principal investigator for the space edge program, to qualify a 5G core for the International Space Station

Experience



Telco sales center of excellence leader Americas

AMD

Jan 2023 - Present (10 months)

Strategic Business Development Director

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Nov 2017 - Jan 2023 (5 years 3 months)

- -Team: Lead a global team of senior Business Development Managers and Chief Technologists promoting HPE IT Hardware across the Telco Market
- -Strategic Business Development: Work in support of the sales teams and partners to penetrate with new solutions, establish technical and business strategies, win and deliver complex Telco solutions
- -Connect &Enable: Ensure HPE has the right expertise with the right knowledge in order to create customer value
- -Product: Gather feedback from the field and engage with the product teams to enable the creation of new products and solutions
- -Executive: Represent the HIT Telco Business Unit in front of sales, customer and partner executives, events and other marketing activities

-Finance: BU's P&L financial and pipeline reporting, present in executive committees, strategize for optimizing business outcomes

Communications, Media and Entertainment Industry Director Latin America and Caribbean

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Nov 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Create and lead the organization focusing on the Telco Sector at HPE for Latin America.

Innovate with products and solutions addressing regional needs.

Define Go To Market Strategy

Coordinate all functions: Sales, Presales, Technical, Product, Marketing, Delivery, Support,

Partnerships

Lead Tiger team to support the countries in the whole sales and delivery lifecycle: Chief Technology

Office, Bid management, Solution architecting, Escalations, Events, C-level relationship...

NFV, IoT, BSS, OSS, Media and Entertainment, SDN, Cloud...

NFV Business Development Manager Americas

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Apr 2014 - Oct 2016 (2 years 7 months)

Business Development Manager Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) in America

Regional Account Principal Americas

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Sep 2010 - Mar 2014 (3 years 7 months)

Regional sales manager for Telco software and services

Software Account Manager

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Jan 2010 - Sep 2010 (9 months)

Account manager for HP SW and Solutions for Telefonica in Spain

Account Principal

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Mar 2006 - Sep 2010 (4 years 7 months)

HP Telco Software and Solutions Account Manager

Consultant

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Jul 2000 - Mar 2006 (5 years 9 months)

HP Consulting and Integration en Telco

Covering various roles, starting from technical consultant to project manager and solution architect Highlight: Deployment of the first ADSL network at Telefonica in Spain, launch of Ya.com and the creation of products like HP Service Activator



Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Sep 1998 - Jul 2000 (1 year 11 months)

Research on Information Systems for the Enterprise

Education



🌄 Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Doctorate, Information Systems

1999 - 2001

Diploma de estudios avanzados en sistemas de información - Master in information systems for enterprises



💂 Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Ingeniero, Telecomunicaciones 1994 - 1999

Colegio San Luis Gonzaga

High School, Science 1990 - 1994

Colegio Cristo Rey Las Moreras

EGB

1980 - 1990

Licenses & Certifications



C-Level Selling by Sales Genetics - sales-genetics GmbH & Co. KG

Skills

Space Systems • Telecommunications • Integration • Pre-sales • Cloud Computing • Management • IT Strategy · Consulting · Sales Management · Business Development

Honors & Awards

Global Telecoms Business magazine awards - Global Telecoms Business

magazine

Jun 2013

Customer Service Innovation Award

http://www.zhilabs.com/new z/telefonica-zhilabs-and-hps-improving-customer-experience-for-millionsof-mobile-users-initiative-wins-customer-service-innovation-award/